i have been
one busy boy so far i've emptied out
this where the melon and pumpkin farm
was
i have rebuilt the farm here inside the
half a mansion and it looked a little
something like this
and i spent probably about six hours
trading with villagers
and what have i got to show for it
probably this is the thing this is what
i don't understand probably way less
than if i had just spent six hours
grinding this yeah
well all of this is for the barge
because that's where i want to start
today's episode so we're gonna head over
there with a inventory full of shulker
boxes
and we're going to get things started
because i have been ever so slightly
ignoring the barge no i've been
restocking it every now and again
but it hasn't had an upgrade
in a really long time and i think
everyone agrees
it's probably about time now i love the
barge i think it's been a bit of a
journey and so i want to keep this i
want to keep
all of these campfires and i want to
keep the fact that it's a floating barge
but it's time for the next upgrade
and i can use these diamonds the
investment diamonds to make that happen
i've got some fresh stock
some new items to sell redstone blocks
being one of them bricks being one of
them and here are my materials to get
started i have a vague idea of what i
want to do here based on something i've
done in the past and i think without
further ado we should just get into it
and you know since we've got this thing
on our hand why don't we do it
with a
[Music]
and there we have it the new and
improved hms ggg although i feel like i
want to now rename this the green
emporium because it is although still
floating on a barge and we still have
that
it just looks so much better so the look
that i've gone for is very much like a
victorian market style and even when
you're inside
this feels absolutely amazing to walk
around essentially it's exactly the same
this hasn't changed at all we're still
on a wooden platform floating in the
shopping district but because of this
it just looks so much better and that
leads me to ask what's next for the
green emporium what could possibly be
next
for the improvement
well i think the answer is to do with
the interior everything's still on
little platforms and there's still a
couple of places
without any stock on at all so there's
definitely still places this can go now
one thing i want to point out is the
actual design of this place you might be
wondering why i went for like this
square in the middle now i like many
other people on the hermitcraft server
we like to fly around i like chops that
you can drop in really easily so i have
intentionally created a giant gap here
so that you can fly in and out easily
and with this shop being like pretty
much in the middle of everything i think
that's a really good feature and since
we've spent a couple of hours upgrading
our shop i think it's finally time to
treat myself to something i've been
putting off buying because it's kind of
expensive and it's actually a trident
from the trident shop here it is loyalty
and channeling and it costs four diamond
blocks it's quite expensive but
i think i can just about afford that oh
man the trident was my thing
in season six and now it's back
we're definitely gonna rename this mumbo
for
meh if anyone happens to get killed by
this it will say you have been killed
by mumbo for mayor speaking of mumbo for
mayor
you may be wondering what's going on
over here with the grumbot
well mumbo hasn't yet had a chance to
have a look at it so i'm hoping i can
introduce him to this later and we can
get the redstone for it it still looks
so cool and he's still like i don't know
i don't know what's going on
i'm grumbot
oh man i really really dig this shop i
actually ended up getting rid of the
front door so that you could fly through
it easily now since we don't have the
grumbot to give us any instructions
what i'm gonna do
is revert back to the original plan
and the plan is the poster the poster is
the plan now i think i've got a clever
way
oh no no no i can't i wasn't i wasn't
gonna change anything
i wasn't gonna change anything but i was
gonna just do a little something
something just a
just a quick there we go
just on the top
just on the top and on here there we go
check it out the poster walls have
definitely
they have definitely begun there we go
this is my shop i'll do what i want i
didn't touch i didn't touch your side
your signs are still there don't worry
and we'll put one in here as well the
green emporium wants you to vote for
mumbo
[Laughter]
this is this is the best and it even
looks like it connects in the middle i
love it and we can even cover up scars
terrible
terrible campaign
boom
this one just says vote scar that's it i
believe i believe scar is actually
streaming right now and he might be
over here yep scar's right there i
wonder if we can hide something right
under his nose i don't know if i have
enough item frames for this but i hope i
do we're done now all i need to do is
convince him to come into the mumbo from
there
it's the mumbo from their infinity room
where did he go
here we go
[Laughter]
hello knock knock
oh oh oh my gosh what the heck
oh that's a shock oh my god there's so
much mustache hi have you heard of have
you heard about our future mayor
[Laughter]
no uh well i'll leave you to ponder it
uh what oh no he's like
he just said tell me more i don't
i don't have more this is this is all i
got the the post is what the
posters will tell you everything you
need to know
that's the plan spam the spam the poster
as soon as they start asking questions
run away run away as fast as possible
this is going to be a very fun event on
the server now that we're back at the
base
i actually do want to do some more work
here not to the interior i actually want
to do stuff that i've been putting off
for a really long time
ah just as the sun sets i'm going to
focus on this bit here
and finally i'm gonna do it
i promise i'm gonna do it i'm going to
put up the walls
on the back of the mansion i probably
won't detail it but putting up the walls
is probably a good place to start
so i think without further ado let's get
in
to another time lapse of the mansion
let's go
[Music]
all of a sudden it looks a lot more
complete that one bit has just finished
off
the symmetry and
the more i build the more i realize how
much more it can expand and how much
bigger it can get
and i'll be honest i don't know when i'm
going to stop because i feel like this
space could be used this space could be
used
this base
these could also go downwards into the
ground the potential of this mansion is
absolutely massive but i've got to pace
myself so next episode i'm hoping to put
in some more details but take a look
round the back i did actually think to
myself while building this
even if i do build the back
you probably don't see it very often
because i just don't come round here
there's no reason for me to work around
the back here but look at that even with
just the walls in it's looking a lot
more full there's a lot of work that
needs doing to the back of this and you
might be looking at what the heck is
going on here with the with the three
different kinds of blocks well this is
called gradient building and this
really helps draw your eyes up from the
darker colors up to the light now this
is actually all over my build but you
probably don't realize it just because
of all of the detailing if we start with
a bit that's a bit more detailed you can
see that goes grey concrete then to wool
then gray concrete powder
and then all the way up to cyan but when
you just look at it as a whole
you don't really notice the gradient
it's only on the very undetailed parts
of the build
that it becomes very very obvious
resources are yet again becoming a bit
of an issue i'm gonna have to get some
more before i can continue working on
the mansion
hopefully next episode more and more of
this will be done because i think it's
gone on more than long enough having
absolutely nothing here bit by bit
though
we will get there
but now we're starting to use the actual
mansion
as a decent place for the farms and
everything else
it's probably about time i did something
that uh
i probably should have done a really
long time ago so in order to explain
what i'm talking about i need to go over
to my camera account to show you
something here we are in my camera
account and there we have the beautiful
mansion
now if we go to where my hobbit hole is
and we go underground
you can see
there's actually not that much natural
caves and they're mostly lit up this was
done for the creeper farm over here if i
turn around
and i look at the mansion
and i go underground hey look there's me
hey me my rocket is stuck on
i don't should we go check what he's
talking about he just he just keeps on
flying
huh
mumbo can't stop flying it turns out you
see how easy it is to get distracted on
this server okay so we have the mansion
but if we go underground here oh man
oh man
so many caves with so many mobs
and look at this
not quite directly underneath it
but
oh man and actually it gets so much
worse there's an enormous abandoned mine
shaft and you can see all the mobs here
causing me lag causing me pain
so
i actually need to go caving to light
all of this up look
done
not done are you ready green
are you ready to take on the challenge
of the undergrowth i'm ready
i feel like i'm at the start of the
season again i haven't had to go caving
well yes
pretty much ever i don't think i went
caving much apart from episode one and
two so i'm getting getting my torches
ready look at me go we'll take some
extra food with us and we need to find
ourselves
an entrance into the system underneath
oh my goodness
i was looking for an entrance and
i found a
pesky bird i haven't seen a pesky bird i
thought you're extinct
i thought you were extinct i thought you
were gone
it's good to see you pesky bird i think
we have got ourselves yep
we got ourselves a way in
the caving
must commence if something tells me this
isn't going to be that fun
[Music]
dig straight down oh no please oh i hit
a hit yes success and we didn't die i
call that a win
oh man
no
no i don't like this i don't like this
[Music]
they just keep coming
oh my goodness
it's not it's full on war
hell
and then every now and again you come
across a room
that looks like it was a mistaken
generation why is there a perfectly
square room here super weird i think
baby zombies win
the competition for worst mob in this
game
even more so than creepers
creepers you could deal with
no not the chest
oh
i feel like i'm gonna be down here for
years
potentially years
i see you
peekaboo
peeking
oh my goodness
oh my goodness this is insane
this is definitely a job that needed
doing oh man and we get gravel to fall
from the ceiling
amazing
come on
this
this is getting ridiculous come on
[Music]
also look at me i'm a mess
i can hear
an insane amount of creatures
yeah get him get him get him get him get
him
yes
oh come on
best way
best way to clear them out
let them do it themselves
[Applause]
[Music]
did you see that
i managed to that's not a joke i managed
to completely destroy stone with my
shovel i don't know how i did that i'm
like minecraft superman or something
that was insane i have video evidence
[Music]
oh
i haven't seen a slime i need to
wait a minute what
are you kidding me i haven't killed a
slime what did i just get what just
happened to me
kill one of every hostile monster you're
telling me i didn't kill a single slime
these are so cute
check it out we are definitely on
green's caving adventure here
all we need now is a theme song
oh there's just something about this
a little blue or it's just so beautiful
i'm gonna need all this all of this is
this a notch apple
is this what a notch is this an i i
don't really know what a notch apple is
but i think it might be this one i think
this is a special one
funny story about last season i found
one of these which is one of the rarest
items in the game you can't get it any
other way
than through loot and i was like
tasty treat tasty treat caves never end
and i'm starting to get lost
oh oh
oh oh no i need tweet tweet
anything
close one
closer no
um
i'm not quite sure what's happened here
oh
we're back i've managed to get my stuff
back but it wasn't easy and the only
casualties that i can really see i got
most of my tools thankfully i got my
mumbo from air fork
but i'm missing my helmet and my elytra
i'm getting
swiftly the heck out of here
i am done caving
i've had enough
there was me trying to try to fly out
i'm nothing without my wings
i'm nothing fortunately for me i have my
own did you die box hasn't got the best
gear but it'll do in a pinch boom boom
and we're back to normal
well that was quite the adventure many
hours spent in a cave and i don't even
know if it's made that much of a
difference i've really come to love
minecraft sunsets they're just
i don't know
peaceful
and there's a scar
right over there
and people like to sleep and ruin it
well i might as well go and get some
books for this helmet and get myself
back up to full scratch
oh there's a new shopping district
portal which
means i think that this portal should
take us
directly to the town hall
boom
it's now the official portal makes this
building a bit more important have we
had any profits
who's responsible for this
i will not have you
vandalize my signs oh my goodness this
has only been up a day and we've we've
had some sales
13 diamonds into the investment pot
i could enchant this by myself but
corrales did give me that really nice
care package so i might as well go to
lookie lookie at my bookie corrales has
made some money off me today oh no
i don't have enough levels oh well
that'll do for now
did you see that
dude
i think that's the first time like i've
like encountered ether we were both just
like
we locked locked eyes for a second
i don't know i don't know why i'm scared
where did he go
he vanished
he straight up vanished from existence
hey hey
i don't want any part of this i'm out
i'm out i'm out oh what is going on
look at this people put i kind of kind
of like this to be this one can stay
this one can stay no
no
don't touch the number from their signs
well we got our books for the helmet
we've done
wow we've done quite a lot today we've
upgraded the shop
we have upgraded the mansion
and we did some lighting up of the caves
i think i could probably do the rest of
that lighting up in a live stream
because that's going to take several
hours to get it done properly
but i'm afraid that is all we have time
for today i hope you enjoyed this
episode i had a lot of fun and i shall
see you in the next episode where
hopefully we'll get our first
instructions
from grumbot
good bye
doing a barrel roll